Zheng (Thomas) Tang

RESEARCH SCIENTIST · COMPUTER VISION EXPERT

4116 12th Ave NE, Apt #204, Seattle, WA 98105, USA

□ (+1) 206-669-5590 | ■ tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | ♣ sites.google.com/site/zhengthomastang | □ zhengthomastang

Summary _

Current Research Scientist at Amazon \cdot Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering from the University of Washington (Advisor: Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang) \cdot Research interests in computer vision and machine learning \cdot 9 months internship at NVIDIA working on city-scale vehicle tracking and ReID with papers accepted at CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 \cdot Winner of 2 of the 3 tracks at the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 \cdot Organizing committee member of the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20 \cdot Finalist best student paper awards in ICPR'16

Education_

UW (University of Washington)

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- Advised by Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-calibration

UW (University of Washington)

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

BUPT (Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

QMUL (Queen Mary University of London)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

Work Experience

Amazon.com Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST

Jul. 2019 - PRESENT

Working on a novel project directed by Prof. Gérard Medioni

NVIDIA Santa Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted at CVPR'19 (oral)
- Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task learning method for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted at ICCV'19
- Supported the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'19 that has attracted 334 academic and industrial research teams from 44 countries
- Joined the organizing committee of the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20, in charge of the MTMC tracking track and the ReID track

University of Washington Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Dec. 2014 - Jun. 2018

- Developed evolutionary camera calibration and clustering-based data association for vehicle tracking using fusion of visual and semantic features that achieved rank #1 in Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis) of the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Designed multi-camera tracking based on fusion of adaptive appearance models, CNN features and license plate information that achieved rank #1 in Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID) of the AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Proposed multi-kernel vehicle tracking based on 3D deformable models that outperformed the state-of-the-art object tracking methods, selected as the winning method of Track 2 (AI City Applications) at the AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17
- Developed a 3D casualty pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation, where two-step evolutionary pose optimization for camera and humans (2EPOCH) is proposed (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Implemented multi-view 3D tracking of soccer players and the ball that enabled real-time soccer analytics (funded by a startup company)
- Developed single-camera people tracking that is robust against occlusion and cluttered background to provide useful features for object ReID across multiple cameras (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

Prism Skylabs San Francisco, CA, USA

Engineering Intern Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Developed adaptive segmentation and tracking based on multi-kernel feedback that achieved top single-camera tracking accuracy (74.82%)
 on the NLPR_MCT benchmark
- Developed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking of humans to automatically back project 2D trajectories into 3D, which received
 2 Finalist Best Student Paper Awards in ICPR'16

November 2, 2019 Zheng (Thomas) Tang · Résumé

Teaching Experience

University of Washington

Seattle, WA, USA Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

Cancún, México

TEACHING ASSISTANT OF EE 508: STOCHASTIC PROCESSES IN ENGINEERING

Designed topics for final projects, provided tutorials on hidden Markov model and held weekly office hours

Publications JOURNAL ARTICLES

MOANA: An online learned adaptive appearance model for robust multiple object tracking in 3D

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 31934-31945. 2019

ESTHER: Joint camera self-calibration and automatic radial distortion correction from tracking of walking humans

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 10754-10766. 2019

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

TCSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang Proc. ICCV, pp. 211-220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Self-calibration of traffic surveillance cameras based on moving vehicle appearance and 3-D vehicle modeling

Na Wang, Haiqing Du, Yong Liu, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICIP, pp. 3064-3068, 2018, Athens, Greece

Inter-camera tracking based on fully unsupervised online learning

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICIP, pp. 2607–2611, 2017, Beijing, China

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115-1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260-265, 2016, Cancún, México

Honors & Awards

2019 People's Choice Award, Code for the Kingdom (C4TK) Hackathon	Seattle, WA, USA
2018 Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis). AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake Citv. UT. USA

2018 Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 Salt Lake City, UT, USA

2017 Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications), AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17

San Francisco, CA, USA 2016 Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16 Cancún, México

2016 Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16

Skills_

Programming C/C++ (expert), Python (expert), Java (proficient), MATLAB (expert), LaTeX (expert)

Deep Learning PyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (proficient), Caffe (proficient)

Languages English (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)